Prashob Jayaprakash

Email/Web Developer

Contact: 9324377294 | Portfolio: <u>Email-Developer</u> | Email Id: prashob.jp@yahoo.com

SUMMARY

Passionate content developer with 4+ years of experience in creating powerful email and web content for better user experiences by leveraging strong HTML/CSS skills coupled with significant experience with client-side libraries such as JavaScript and jQuery. Mindful of W3C coding standards and cross platform, cross-browser HTML compatibility while designing and developing web content. Worked on more than 30+ projects for brands like Merck, Sanofi, Johnson, and Johnson for EMEA Region.

SKILLS

- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript, jQuery
- Litmus
- Google Analytics
- Responsive Design & Media Query
- Salesforce Marketing Cloud
- Search Engine Optimization
- Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Aftereffects
- Excel, Word, and PowerPoint

WORK EXPERIENCE

Email Developer
Self-Employed (Freelancing)

Nov 2020 - July 2022

- Hand coded/implemented HTML emails and innovative landing pages using clean, standards-compliant code.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, Marketing Communications, Creative Operations and Editors to ensure campaigns accuracy and is in accordance with quality specification.
- Tested, troubleshot, revised code when necessary to ensure campaigns rendered properly across multiple email clients, browsers, and mobile devices.
- Sliced and optimized images for HTML emails using Photoshop.
- Integrated JavaScript (jQuery) functionality from existing libraries to enhance user experience.

- Managed and maintain campaigns in email archive database (MySQL).
- Ensured projects are delivered on schedule to meet strict deadlines.

Computer Programmer (Email/Web Developer) Business Alert Trading LLC, Dubai, UAE

June 2018 - Sept 2020

- Designed, edited HTML Email Templates for email campaigns and newsletters.
- Debugged issues discovered while testing, tested site for cross browser compatibility (IE, Firefox, Chrome, Safari).
- Created color gradient schemes, custom shapes, and web graphics with Photoshop.
- Design and developed videos/gifs in Aftereffects.
- Used FileZilla to FTP web sites.

Web Developer

Accenture, Mumbai

July 2017 - Oct 2017

- Design and develop web applications and email campaigns.
- Manual testing of all applications for smooth functioning.
- Establishing best practices for exceptional email deliverability across multiple Ips.
- Conduct quality assurance testing for various device types.

Web Developer

Lionbridge Technologies Pvt Ltd, Mumbai

Jan 2016 - Aug 2016

- Requirement gathering and documentation.
- Design and develop e-learning web applications.
- Creating gifs and image editing on Adobe software's.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's in computer science, 2014 Mumbai University, India

LANGUAGES

- English
- Hindi
- Malayalam

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the information and details provided in this resume are correct and inclusive to the best of my knowledge and belief.